The car has reshaped our cities.
汽车重塑了我们的城市。
It seems to offer autonomy for everyone.
它似乎能让每个人都享有自主权。
There is something almost delightful in the detachment from reality of advertisements showing mass-produced cars marketed as symbols of individuality and of freedom when most of their lives will be spent making short journeys on choked roads.
广告展示批量生产的汽车，把它们当作个性与自由的象征来推销，而这些汽车一生中的大部分时间都将在拥堵的道路上短途行驶；这种广告与现实的脱节，几乎有几分令人愉快。
For all the fuss made about top speeds, cornering ability and acceleration, the most useful gadgets on a modern car are those which work when you’re going very slowly: parking sensors, sound systems, and navigation apps which will show a way around upcoming traffic jams.
尽管人们对最高时速、过弯能力和加速性能大做文章，现代汽车上最有用的装置却是那些在你开得很慢时起作用的东西：泊车传感器、音响系统，以及能指出如何绕开前方交通拥堵的导航应用。
This seems to be one of the few areas where the benefit of sharing personal information comes straight back to the sharer: because these apps know where almost all the users are, and how fast they are moving almost all the time, they can spot traffic congestion very quickly and suggest ways round it.
在少数几个领域里，分享个人信息的好处会直接回到分享者自己身上，这似乎就是其中之一：由于这些应用几乎随时都知道几乎所有用户身在何处、移动速度有多快，它们能很快发现交通拥堵，并就如何绕开拥堵给出建议。
The problem comes when everyone is using a navigation app which tells them to avoid everyone else using the same gadget.
一旦人人都在用导航应用，而应用又让他们避开其他所有使用同样装置的人，问题就来了。
Traffic jams often appear where no one has enough information to avoid them.
交通拥堵往往出现在谁都没有足够信息加以避开的地方。
When a lucky few have access to the knowledge, they will benefit greatly.
少数幸运儿能获得这些信息时，就会大大受益。
But when everyone has perfect information, traffic jams simply spread onto the side roads that seem to offer a way round them.
但如果人人都掌握完备的信息，交通拥堵只会蔓延到那些看似能绕开拥堵的小路上。
This new congestion teaches us two things.
这种新的拥堵给了我们两点启示。
The first is that the promises of technology will never be realised as fully as we hope; they will be limited by their unforeseen and unintended consequences.
第一点是，技术的承诺永远不会像我们希望的那样充分兑现；它们会受制于自身带来的、未曾预见也并非有意造成的后果。
Sitting in a more comfortable car in a different traffic jam is pleasant but hardly the liberation that once seemed to be promised.
坐在一辆更舒适的车里、陷在另一场交通拥堵中，固然惬意，却很难说是当初似乎许诺过的那种解放。
The second is that self-organisation will not get us where we want to go.
第二点是，自发组织不会把我们带到想去的地方。
The efforts of millions of drivers to get ahead do not miraculously produce a situation in which everyone does better than before, but one in which almost everyone does rather worse.
数百万司机为抢先所做的努力，并不会奇迹般地带来人人处境都胜过从前的局面，而是会带来几乎人人处境都差了不少的局面。
Central control and collective organisation can produce smoother and fairer outcomes, though even that much is never guaranteed.
集中控制和集体组织能够带来更顺畅、更公平的结果，尽管就连这一点也从来无法保证。
Similar limits can be foreseen for the much greater advances promised by self-driving cars.
可以预见，自动驾驶汽车所许诺的那些大得多的进步，也会面临类似的局限。
Last week, one operated by the taxi company Uber struck and killed a woman pushing her bicycle across a wide road in Arizona.
上周，出租车公司优步运营的一辆自动驾驶汽车在亚利桑那州撞死了一名推着自行车横穿一条宽阔马路的女子。
This was the first recorded death involving a car which was supposed to be fully autonomous.
这是有记录以来首起与本应完全自动驾驶的汽车有关的死亡事故。
Experts have said that it suggests a “catastrophic failure” of technology.
专家称，这表明技术出现了“灾难性故障”。
Increasingly, even Silicon Valley has to acknowledge the costs of the intoxicating hurry that characterises its culture.
就连硅谷也越来越不得不承认，其文化特有的那种令人陶醉的匆忙是有代价的。
What traffic teaches us is that reckless and uncontrolled change is as likely to harm us as it is to benefit us, and that thoughtful regulation is necessary for a better future.
交通给我们的启示是：鲁莽而不受控制的变革，造福我们的可能性有多大，伤害我们的可能性就有多大；要想拥有更美好的未来，深思熟虑的监管必不可少。